<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on code and stuff</title>
    <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on code and stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicholas Dumas 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 10:45:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ndumas.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Path of Market: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/path-of-market1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 10:45:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/path-of-market1/</guid>
      <description>Path of Exile is an ARPG similar to Diablo: procedurally generated maps, kill monsters to get loot so you can kill monsters faster. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty fun and offers a really flexible build system that allows for a lot of creativity in how you achieve your goals. Of particular interest is the API exposed by the development team.
Stashes Each character has a set of &amp;ldquo;stashes&amp;rdquo;. These are storage boxes which can be flagged a public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus Primer</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/prom-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 14:56:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/prom-primer/</guid>
      <description>Querying Basics Queries run against metrics, which are sets of timeseries data. They have millisecond granularity and are stored as floating point values.
Using Queries Queries reference individual metrics and perform some analysis on them. Most often you use the rate function to &amp;ldquo;bucket&amp;rdquo; a metric into time intervals. Once the metric in question has been bucketed into time intervals, you can do comparisons.
(rate(http_response_size_bytes[1m])) &amp;gt; 512 This query takes the size of http responses in bytes and buckets it into one minute intervals and drops any data points smaller than 512 bytes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Noise</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/making-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 19:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/making-noise/</guid>
      <description>The Conceit I&amp;rsquo;ve written about Genesis before, but it&amp;rsquo;s got a lot of complexity attached to it, and the roadmap I originally laid out has shifted a bit. For this post I&amp;rsquo;m focusing solely on Phase 1, the generation of geography. This is obviously a fundamental starting point, and it has roadblocked my progress on Genesis for quite some time ( somewhere on the order of 8 years or so ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/data-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 14:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/data-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>interfaces I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Go&amp;rsquo;s interfaces. They&amp;rsquo;re really simple and don&amp;rsquo;t require a lot of legwork.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 type Mover interface { func Move(x, y int) (int, int) } type Dog struct { Name string } func (d Dog) Move(x, y int) (int, int) { return x, y } Dog is now a Mover! No need for keywords like implements. The compiler just checks at the various boundaries in your app, like struct definitions and function signatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Quantize</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/golang-quantize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 17:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/golang-quantize/</guid>
      <description>The Goal Before going too deep into the implementation details of Genesis, I&amp;rsquo;ll touch on the high level aspect of quantization. Quantization is a technique used to map arbitrary inputs into a well defined output space. This is, practically speaking, a hash function. When the term &amp;lsquo;quantization&amp;rsquo; is used, however, it&amp;rsquo;s typically numeric in nature. Quantization is typically used in audio/image processing to compress inputs for storage or transmission.
Quantizing OpenSimplex My use case is a little less straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selinux and Nginx</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/selinux-and-nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 16:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/selinux-and-nginx/</guid>
      <description>SELinux DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s Fedora droplets include SELinux. I don&amp;rsquo;t know a great deal about SELinux but it&amp;rsquo;s presumably a good thing for helping prevent privilege escalations and so on. Unfortunately, it can be troublesome when trying to do simple static site stuff with nginx.
nginx With Fedora and nginx and selinux all in use simultaneously, you are allowed to tell nginx to serve files that are owned/grouped under a user other than nginx&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genesis Flags</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/genesis-flags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 03:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/genesis-flags/</guid>
      <description>Genesis Genesis is a project I’ve spent a great deal of time thinking about and working on for a while with little progress. I’m recycling my old Github blog post because it still highlights the overall design plan. I’ve since altered the project to use Golang instead of CPython. The change is inspired by a desire/need for improved performance, in my view Golang is the perfect tool to accomplish this goal and is the natural next step in my progression as a developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing Up Gogs</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/standing-up-gogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 23:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/standing-up-gogs/</guid>
      <description>The Reveal It took me way longer than I&amp;rsquo;d like to admit but I finally discovered why I was not able to properly reverse proxy a subdomain ( git.ndumas.com ). As it turns out, SELinux was the culprit. I wanted to write a short post about this partly to reinforce my own memory and maybe to make this sort of thing easier to find for others encountering &amp;lsquo;mysterious&amp;rsquo; issues when operating on SELinux Fedora installations like Digital Ocean droplets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 23:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been programming with a passion for the last 15 years. I started with Python 2.2 or so and stuck with that for a good while, I also spent a few years doing web development work and most recently added Golang to my kit.
This Site This site is going to be a portfolio/showroom for my projects. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to find clever ways to interact with my tools through the browser to take advantage of the optimizations and growing array of high power tools being baked into browsers like Chrome and Firefox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genesis Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://ndumas.com/posts/genesis-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ndumas.com/posts/genesis-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I was working on an idea for a MUD; the general idea was to build a game with detailed &amp;lsquo;inhabited&amp;rsquo; areas such as cities and dungeons as well as expansive wilderness regions for exploring and claiming by players. Naturally, I realized that doing this by hand would be unbearably tedious. A semi-realistic MUD world could contain 4,000,000 rooms; manually creating &amp;ldquo;Meadowy Plains #1421&amp;rdquo; would be error-prone and would drain the creative ability of a human.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
